Guide to the Stanford University, W. W. Hansen Laboratories, Klystron Reports and Patents
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, W. W. Hansen Laboratories, klystron reports and patents
1936-1949
SC0372
Stanford University. W.W. Hansen Laboratories.
Stanford University. W.W. Hansen Laboratory of Physics.
0.75 Linear feet
Reports generated at the Sperry Gyroscope Company on various aspects of the Klystron, 1945-1947; photocopy of the Wave Guide Handbook, 1944-1945, prepared by the Radiation Laboratory at Massachusetts Institute of Technology; paper by V.F. Kovalenko on the history of microwave electron-beam tubes, 1940; and printed patents for the various elements of the Klystron, 1936-1949.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer, 1990.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical History
Brothers Sigurd and Russell Varian worked in collaboration with Prof. William W. Hansen beginning in 1937 to invent and perfect the Klystron, a device for generating high-power microwaves. Much of the work was conducted at the Sperry Gyroscope Company.
Description of the Collection
Reports generated at the Sperry Gyroscope Company on various aspects of the Klystron, 1945-1947; photocopy of the Wave Guide Handbook, 1944-1945, prepared by the Radiation Laboratory at Massachusetts Institute of Technology; paper by V.F. Kovalenko on the history of microwave electron-beam tubes, 1940; and printed patents for the various elements of the Klystron, 1936-1949.
Access Terms
Kovalenko, V.F. (Viktor Fedorovich).; Massachusetts Institute of Technology. Radiation Laboratory.; Sperry Gyroscope Company, inc.; Stanford University. W.W. Hansen Laboratories.; Stanford University. W.W. Hansen Laboratory of Physics.; Klystrons.; Microwave tubes.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Tables of contents from original binders. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Wave Guide Handbook, sections 1-3, 1944-45 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Sections, 4-24 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Sections, 25-34 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Sections, 35-end (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Kovalenko, V. F. "History of the Development of Microwave Electro-Beam Tubes,", 1940 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Sperry Gyroscope Company Reports
    - Characteristics of the Type 410R Klystron, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - The Velocity Spectrograph and the Measurement of Electronic Beam Loading in Klystron, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - calculation of Q and Shunt Impedance of Reentrant cavities, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Space Charge Effects in Reflex Klystrons, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Patents for various elements of the Klystron, 1936-1949 (Box 2, Folder 5)